==TLF HALFCD TEAM==
-=双字幕调校:刘晗=-
仅供交流，请勿商用
[Thundering]
[Clock gongs]
[Gong]
让我们先隔开头颅. .
If we look at the base of a brain
来看看脑的底部. .
which has just been removed from a skull
很显然地我们 就能看见小小的中脑
there's very little midbrain that we can actually see.
不错，正如我们上周讲到的. .
Yet, as I demonstrated in my lecture last week
如果把聂叶的底部. .
if the under aspects of the temporal lobes
撒开. .
are gently pulled apart...
我们就能看见脑的上部的干
the upper portion of the stem of the brain can be seen.
也就是我们说的脑干 它是由中脑. .
The so-called brainstem consists of the midbrain
一圆形的脑桥. .
a rounded protrusion called the pons...
以及一向下的尖端细的茎 也就是我们说的延髓. .
and a stalk tapering downwards called the medulla oblongata
延髓通过枕骨大孔 向头颅外延伸. .
which passes out of the skull through the foramen magnum...
当然，它的后端. .
and becomes, of course...
就会与脊髓相联
the spinal cord.
有什么疑问吗？
Are there any questions before we proceed?
我有个问题，弗兰肯斯坦恩
I have one question, Dr. Frankenstein.
是弗朗肯斯丁恩
That's Fronkensteen.
什么？
I beg your pardon?
我的名字-- 是弗朗肯斯丁恩
My name... it's pronounced Fronkensteen.
难道你不是著名的. .
Aren't you the grandson...
的医生维克托. 弗兰肯斯坦恩的孙子吗. .
of the famous Dr. Victor Frankenstein
他曾在墓地 挖出一具刚埋的尸体. .
who went into graveyards, dug up freshly buried corpses
然后把那些死去的器官--
and transformed dead components
是的，是的
Yes! Yes!
好的
Yes.
我们大家都知道他做过什么
We all know what he did.
但你应该记住的是我. .
But I'd rather be remembered...
为科学作出的一些小小的贡献. .
for my own small contributions to science...
而不是我巧好跟一个. .
and not because of my accidental relationship
很有名的疯子. .
to a famous...
有亲戚关系的事
cuckoo.
[Laughter]
不妨说说你想问的问题吧？
You mind telling me your question?
先生，我对于. .
STUDENT: Sir, I'm not sure I understand the distinction
反射性及自律性的 脉冲之间的关系不是很明白
between reflexive and voluntary nerve impulses.
很好
Very good.
我们今天的课 正是要展示这一区别.
Since our lab today demonstrates just that distinction
那我们何不继续下去呢
why don't we proceed?
[Gong]
进来的这位是黑尔先生 他是第一次到我们的实验课来.
Mr. Hilltop here, with whom I have never worked
而且之前我也没给过他任何的暗示.
nor given any prior instructions to
他很乐意为我们今天下午的课. .
has graciously offered his services
提供一些帮助
for this afternoon's demonstration.
黑尔先生 你可以翻身爬起来. .
Mr. Hilltop, would you hop up on your feet
站到桌子旁吗？
and stand beside this table?
很好
Nice hopping.
黑尔先生. .
Mr. Hilltop...
可以抬起. .
would you raise...
你的左腿吗？
your left knee, please?
你们刚刚看到的就是自律性脉冲
You have just witnessed a voluntary nerve impulse.
一开始是由大脑的皮层受到刺激. .
It begins as a stimulus from the cerebral cortex
通过脑干 然后向各个神经肌肉发送信息
passes through the brainstem and to the various muscles involved.
黑尔先生，你可以放下腿了
Mr. Hilltop, you may lower your knee.
反射性的脉冲. .
Reflex movements...
是人体自然的反应. .
are those which are made independently of the will
但它是跟. .
but are carried out along pathways
周边神经系统
which pass between the peripheral nervous system
和中枢神经系统有关的
and the central nervous system.
你这下流的老色鬼
You filthy, rotten, yellow son of a bitch!
[Students gasp]
我们自己并没有意识到这种电脉冲
We are not aware of these impulses.
也没有让它们. .
Neither do we intend them...
来刺激我们肌肉的收缩
to carry out our contraction of muscles.
但如你们自己看到的 它们是自己无意识中发出的
Yet, as you can see, they work by themselves.
如果我们用一种普通的金属夹
But what if we blocked the nerve impulse
在局部地方施加一点压力--
by simply applying local pressure
来封闭这种脉冲动
which can be done with any ordinary metal clamp
就在这个突起的地方. .
just at the swelling...
也就是后部的神经根--
on the posterior nerve roots...
用差不多. .
for, oh, say...
五六秒的时间吧？
five or six seconds?
你他妈的王八蛋
Why, you mother-grabbing bastard!
你们可以看得到 一点反应都没有了
As you can see, all communication is shut off.
[Mr. Hilltop moans]
[Students gasp]
尽管医学科技越来越先进
In spite of our mechanical magnificence
但是如果没有电脉冲. .
if it were not for this continuous stream
给我们提供生命力. .
of motor impulses
那我们. .
we would collapse...
就会像一束. . .绿菜花！
like a bunch of... broccoli!
Aieeeaah!
所以，要注意的是--
In conclusion, it should be noted...
多给他一些钱
Give him an extra dollar.
多给一些钱，好的，先生
ATTENDANT: Extra dollar. Yes, sir.
--比起其它的一些伤来. .
FRANKENSTEIN: That any more than common injury
神经根受到的伤更严重. .
to the nerve root is always serious
因为只要有一根 神经纤维受到伤害. .
because once a nerve fiber is severed
那么无论什么名丹妙药. .
there is no way in heaven or on earth
都无法起死回生
to regenerate life back into it.
下课之前还有什么想要问的吗？
Are there any last questions before we leave?
弗兰肯--
Uh, Dr. Frank...
-弗朗肯斯丁恩医生 -什么？
- Fronkensteen. - Yes?
达尔文曾把一根面条. .
Isn't it true...
放在一个玻璃容器. .
that Darwin preserved a piece of vermicelli...
然后通过一些特殊的方法. .
in a glass case...
那根面条开始随意运动. .
until, by some extraordinary means...
难道这不是真的吗？
it actually began to move with a voluntary motion?
是蚯蚓还是意大利细面条呢？
Are you speaking of the worm or the spaghetti?
蚯蚓，先生
Why, the worm, sir.
是的，当我是个学生的时候. .
FRANKENSTEIN: Yes. I did read something of that incident
也读到过这种事. .
when I was a student...
但是你必须记住的是. .
but you have to remember that a worm...
蚯蚓是极少极少的一种例外. .
with very few exceptions...
它毕竟不是人
is not a human being.
[Students laughing]
但是你祖父所研究的学术--
But wasn't that the whole basis of your grandfather's work
不就是让死去的机体组织再复活吗？
the reanimation of dead tissue?
我祖父是个病态的人
My grandfather was a very sick man.
但你既然是他的孙子. .
STUDENT: But as a Fronkensteen...
难道就对此事一点好奇都没有吗？
aren't you the least bit curious about it?
难道让一个人起死回生. .
Doesn't the bringing back to life what was once dead
就激不起你的一点点兴趣？
hold any intrigue for you?
你所说的这些完全 就是一些无意义的疯话. .
You're are talking about the nonsensical ravings
极端愚蠢的话
of a lunatic mind.
死了就是死了
Dead is dead!
但可以看看是否可以从内脏着手
STUDENT: But look what's been done with hearts and kidneys.
内脏是可以修复的玩具
Hearts and kidneys are tinker toys!
我讲的是中枢神经系统
I'm talking about the central nervous system!
但，先生--
But, sir...
我是个科学家 不是哲学家
I am a scientist, not a philosopher!
你有更多的机会 修复受损的神经系统. .
You have more chance of reanimating this scalpel
而不是让这把刀复活
than you have of mending a broken nervous system!
但是你祖父的学术怎么解释呢，先生？
But what about your grandfather's work, sir?
我祖父的学术是胡扯蛋
FRANKENSTEIN: My grandfather's work was doo-doo!
我对死人不感兴趣
I am not interested in death!
我唯一关心的是. .
The only thing that concerns me...
现在的还活着的人们
is the preservation of life!
下. .
Class...
课. .
is...
吧
dismissed.
[Applause]
弗兰肯斯坦恩医生
FALKSTEIN: Dr. Frankenstein.
是弗朗肯斯丁恩
FRANKENSTEIN: That's Fronkensteen.
我是哥特
My name is Gerhardt Falkstein.
我千里条条. .
I've traveled 5,000 miles...
为你带回了你曾祖父. .
to bring you the will of your great-grandfather...
巴朗.波福特. .
Baron Bofort...
范.弗兰肯斯坦恩的遗嘱
von Frankenstein.
我亲爱的
ELIZABETH: Oh, my sweet darling.
我最最亲爱的
Oh, my dearest love.
我会珍惜这一短暂的离别时刻
I'll count the hours that you're away.
我也是
FRANKENSTEIN: Oh, darling, so will I.
不要吻唇
Not on the lips.
什么？
What?
我就要去参加 巴比和尼克的派对
I'm going to that party at Nana and Nicky's later.
不想弄坏了我的口红
I don't want to smear my lipstick.
-你能理解吗 -当然
- You understand. - Of course.
准备起程
CONDUCTOR: All aboard!
亲爱的
Oh, dear!
好了，我想我该走了
FRANKENSTEIN: Well, I guess this is it.
弗勒迪，亲爱的. .
Freddy, darling...
我真不知该如何 在这么短的时间内. .
how can I say in a few minutes...
说出要靠一生 才能理解的情感的话？
what has taken me a lifetime to understand?
为何不试试看？
Won't you try?
好的
All right.
你得到了，先生
You've got it, mister.
我是你的--整个我的人，我的心 我还能说些什么呢？
我的爱人--
My sweet love...
发型！发型 我刚做好的
The hair! The hair! Just been set.
对不起，对不起
Sorry. Sorry.
我希望你喜欢传统的婚礼
I hope you like old-fashioned weddings.
我喜欢传统的婚夜
I prefer old-fashioned wedding nights.
你这个被宠坏的孩子
Oh! You're incorrigible!
这就是说. .
Does that mean...
你爱我？
you love me?
你说呢
You bet your boots it does.
我的宝贝，我唯一的爱人--
Oh, my only love...
塔夫绸，亲爱的
Taffeta, darling.
塔夫绸，甜心
Taffeta, sweetheart.
不，我说的是我的衣裙是塔夫绸
No, the dress is taffeta.
很容易起皱的
- It wrinkles so easily. - Oh.
准备起程了
All aboard!
又是那个令人讨厌的人
There's that horrid man again.
快点吧，在我还没做出蠢事之前
Oh, hurry now, before I make a fool of myself.
指甲
Aah! The nails!
对不起
Sorry.
[Conductor closes door]
再见，亲爱的
Good-bye, darling.
再见，弗勒迪
Good-bye, Freddy.
亲爱的
Darling!
[Coughing]
哈利，他又干出那种蠢事了
WOMAN: Harry, he was at it again.
你想让我怎么样
HARRY: What do you want me to do?
每天都这样
WOMAN: Every day!
让他去吧，让他去吧
HARRY: Let him! Let him!
下一站，纽约
CONDUCTOR: New York next!
要下车的乘客，请作好下车准备
Everybody out for New York!
他又干出那种蠢事了
WOMAN: Hans, er nacht un schoen weider.
你想让我怎么样
HANS: Was lichsten sie mich tun?
每天都这样
WOMAN: Jeden tag!
让他去吧，让他去吧
HANS: Lasse sei ihn. Lasse sei ihn!
下一站，特兰西瓦尼亚
CONDUCTOR: Transylvania nachst!
要下车的乘客请作好下车准备
Nenne aufsteigen fur Transylvania!
下一站，特兰西瓦尼亚
Transylvania nachst!
要下车的乘客请作好下车准备
Nenne aufsteigen fur Transylvania!
请问一下，男孩
Pardon me, boy.
这是特兰西瓦尼亚火车站吗？
Is this the Transylvania station?
是的，是的
Ja! Ja! Track 29!
需要擦鞋吗？
Oh, can I give you a shine?
Uh...
不，不用了，谢谢你
No, thanks.
[Train pulling away]
[Whooooooosh-thump]
弗兰肯斯坦恩医生？
Dr. Frankenstein?
[Thunder]
弗朗肯斯丁恩
Fronkensteen.
不要愚弄我
You're putting me on.
发音应该是弗朗肯斯丁恩
FRANKENSTEIN: No. It's pronounced Fronkensteen.
人们通常叫你弗欧迪吗？
Do you also say Froderick?
不，弗勒迪
No. Frederick.
是不是弗欧迪.弗兰肯斯坦恩？
Why isn't it Froderick Fronkensteen?
不是的，是弗勒迪.弗朗肯斯丁恩
It isn't. It's Frederick Fronkensteen.
我明白了
I see.
你一定是伊哥尔
You must be lgor.
不，是艾哥尔
No, it's pronounced l-gor.
但他们告诉我是伊哥尔
But they told me it was lgor.
他们说错了，不是吗？
They were wrong then, weren't they?
. .是哥特先生让你来的？
Uh..you were sent by Herr Falkstein, weren't you?
是的
Yes.
我祖父曾是你祖父的助手
My grandfather used to work for your grandfather.
那太好了
How nice.
是的，我们是世交了
Of course, the rates have gone up.
不错，不错
Of course. Of course.
我想我们会相处得很愉快的
I'm sure we'll get along splendidly.
Oh!
对不起. . .我. .
Sorry... l...
uh...
我并不是想羞辱你. .
I don't mean to embarrass you...
我是个相当出名的外科手术医生
but I'm a rather brilliant surgeon.
也许我可以给你的驼背做点手术
Perhaps I could help you with that hump.
什么驼背？
What hump?
我们走吧
Let's go.
让我来，先生
Allow me, master.
非常感谢
FRANKENSTEIN: Oh, thanks very much.
从这边走
Walk this way.
这边走
This way.
[Thunder]
我想你坐在后面会更舒服点
IGOR: I think you'll be more comfortable in the rear.
FRANKENSTEIN: Oh.
那是什么
- Oof! - What was that?
也许是英佳
Oh, that would be Inga.
哥特先生认为你也许需要一个. .
Herr Falkstein thought you might need...
临时的实验室助手
a laboratory assistant temporarily.
Oh.
Whew!
哈罗
Hello.
你喜欢在干草里打滚吗？
Would you like a roll in the hay?
很有趣的
It's fun.
滚，滚，滚
[Singing] Roll, roll.
在干草里滚
Roll in the hay. Roll, roll.
FRANKENSTEIN: Waaah!
在干草里滚
[Lnga singing] Roll in the hay.
[Thunder]
INGA: Ohh.
我怕闪电
I sometimes am afraid of the lightning.
只是大气放电而矣
FRANKENSTEIN: Just an atmospheric discharge.
没什么好怕的
- Oh. - Nothing to be afraid of.
ANIMAL: Ooowwwwoooooeeeee!
是狼人吗
INGA: Werewolf!
狼人？
FRANKENSTEIN: Werewolf?
那儿
There.
什么？
FRANKENSTEIN: What?
那个地方
There wolf.
那个城堡
There castle.
为什么要到那儿？
Why are you talking that way?
我以为你想去
I thought you wanted to.
不，我并不想去
No. I don't want to.
那听从您的安排
Suit yourself. I'm easy.
[Thunder]
Well...
就在那边
there it is.
家
IGOR: Home.
[Thunder]
[Loud boom]
这是什么鬼门环
FRANKENSTEIN: What knockers!
INGA: Ohh...
谢谢你，医生
thank you, Doctor.
没关系
FRANKENSTEIN: Oh. That's all right.
我是布鲁切
I am Frau Blucher.
[Thunder]
[Whinnying]
安静
IGOR: Steady!
你好？我是弗朗肯斯丁恩医生
How do you do? I am Dr. Frankenstein.
这是我的助手
This is my assistant.
英佳，这位是布鲁切
Inga, may I present Frau Blucher?
[Horses whinny]
它们中什么邪了？
FRANKENSTEIN: What's got into them?
你的房间已经准备好了
Your rooms have been prepared, Herr Doktor.
请跟我来. .
If you will follow me...
艾哥尔. .
FRANKENSTEIN: Lgor...
一会儿把行李拿上来，好吗
would you bring the bags when you're finished?
好的，先生
IGOR: Yes, master.
您先请，布鲁切
After you, Frau Blucher.
[Horses whinny]
布鲁切
Blucher!
[Horses whinny]
跟着我
BLUCHER: Follow me, please.
跟蜡烛近一些
Stay close to the candles.
那些楼梯不好走
The staircase can be treacherous.
这是你的房间
BLUCHER: and this is your room.
这是你祖父曾住过的
It was your grandfather Victor's room.
我知道
FRANKENSTEIN: I see.
. . .好像没几本书
Well... seem to be quite a few books.
这曾是维克托--
BLUCHER: This was Victor's...
男爵的医药图书室
the baron's medical library.
我祖父的私人图书室在哪？
And where is my grandfather's private library?
什么意思？
BLUCHER: What do you mean?
这些书很一般
Well, these books are all very general.
每个医生都会有的
Any doctor might have them around.
这是我知道的唯一一个图书室. .
BLUCHER: This is the only library I know of
弗兰肯斯坦医生
Dr. Frankenstone.
弗朗肯丁恩
Fronkensteen.
好的，  我们会记住的
Well, we'll see.
晚安
Good night.
睡觉之前想喝点白兰地吗？
Would the doctor care for a brandy before retiring?
不用了
No.
谢谢你
Thank you.
或者. .
Some warm milk...
想喝杯热牛奶？
perhaps?
不用了
No.
非常感谢你
Thank you very much.
不，谢谢
No, thanks.
阿华田？
Ovaltine?
什么都不用
Nothing!
谢谢你
Thank you.
我只是有些累
I'm a little tired.
那我就道声晚安
Then I will say good night.
晚安
Good night!
晚安，亲爱的
BLUCHER: Good night, darling.
晚安，医生
Good night, Herr Doktor.
晚安，布鲁切
Good night, Frau Blucher.
[Horses whinny]
不，不，不
No, no, no.
不，不，不，不，不，不，不
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
不，不，不，不，不，不，不，不
我不是弗兰肯斯坦恩
I'm not a Frankenstein.
I am not a Frankenstein!
我是弗朗肯斯丁恩
I'm a Fronkensteen!
不要给我
Don't give me that!
我不相信命运
I don't believe in fate!
我不会说的
And I won't say it.
好的，你赢了
All right. You win.
你赢了，我认输
You win. I give.
我认输，我认输
I'll say it. I'll say it.
我认输
I'll say it.
命运，命运
Destiny! Destiny!
我无处可逃
No escaping that for me!
命运，命运
Destiny! Destiny!
我无处可逃
No escaping that for me!
命运，命运
Destiny... destiny...
无处可逃
No escaping...
弗朗肯斯丁恩医生，醒醒
Dr. Frankenstein, wake up.
怎么了？
What is it?
你在做恶梦
You were having a nachtmare.
这种奇怪的音乐从哪来的？
What's that strange music?
我不知道
INGA: I have no idea.
听起来好像是从. .
It seems to be coming...
书架后面传来的
from behind the bookcase.
书架后面
Behind the bookcase.
亲爱的，把长袍递给我
Hand me that robe, would you, dear?
[Distant violin music]
你说的对
You were right.
是从墙后传出来的
It's coming from behind this wall.
在哪呢？
Where is it?
什么？
INGA: What?
肯定会有机关的
There's always a device.
如果我能碰对机关--
If I can just spot the triggering mechanism...
哈罗
Hello.
这边听起来更清晰些
It seems louder over here.
把那支蜡烛给我
Hand me that candle, will you?
把. . .蜡烛. . .放回去
FRANKENSTEIN: Put... the candle... back!
好的
FRANKENSTEIN: All right.
我想我找到它了
I think I have it figured out now.
把蜡烛拿出来. .
Take out the candle...
我要用身体把这个书架挡住
and I'll block the bookcase with my body.
[Crash]
仔仔细细听我说
[High-pitched voice] Listen to me very carefully.
不要把蜡烛放回去
Don't put the candle back.
用你最大的力. .
With all of your might...
推书架的另一面
shove against the other side of the bookcase.
听明白了吗？
Is that perfectly clear?
明白了
I think so.
做得好，女孩
Good girl.
把蜡烛放回去
INGA: Put the candle back!
看，医生，有条通道
Oh, look, Doctor. A passageway!
音乐就是从下面传出来的
That music's coming from down there.
我最好去看看
I'd better take a look.
我跟你一块去
Let me come with you.
我不想一个人待在这
I don't want to stay alone.
把你的衣服穿好 跟我来
Close your robe and follow me.
医生，蜡烛
Oh, Doctor. The candle.
好主意
Good thinking.
我们拿这支
Let's try this one.
后退
Stand back!
[Violin music playing]
[Thunder]
INGA: Ohhh!
[Screeching]
不用害怕
FRANKENSTEIN: Don't be frightened.
只不过是只老鼠
It's just a rat.
一只恶心的粘乎乎的老鼠
A filthy, slimy rat!
上帝
FRANKENSTEIN: Good Lord!
INGA: Ohhh!
[Singing] I...
ain't got no body.
And nobody cares for me.
Yakka tak ta yakka tak ta ha.
-艾哥尔！ -弗勒迪
- Igor! - Froderick!
你是怎么到这来的？
How did you get here?
从升降机下来的
Through the dumbwaiter.
我听到一种很奇怪的音乐
I heard the strangest music.
就跟随着它下来了
I just followed it down.
称它为. . .一个肉峰
Call it... a hunch.
Badoom-chi!
一定有其他人来过这
INGA: Someone else must have been here.
不错
FRANKENSTEIN: It would seem that way.
那边还有另外一扇门
There's the only other door.
等等，先生
IGOR: Wait, master.
一定很危险
It might be dangerous.
你先进
You go first.
这个地方没电的吗？
FRANKENSTEIN: Aren't there any lights in this place?
有两个很难看的开关
IGOR: Two nasty-looking switches here.
我不先碰
I'm not going to be first.
FRANKENSTEIN: Ohh.
你这双该死的眼睛
Damn your eyes!
太晚了
Too late.
INGA: Ohhh.
这就是那个所有事情发生的地点
FRANKENSTEIN: So this is where it all happened.
想想看
VICTOR: Just think.
一个死了的头脑. .
A dead brain...
会再一具新的身体里复活
ready to live again in a new body.
看，没有血，没有腐烂
Look. No blood. No decomposition.
只有几处缝合的地方
Just a few sutures.
打开总开关
Throw the main switch!
是，先生
ASSISTANT: Yes, master.
太乱了
FRANKENSTEIN: What a filthy mess!
几幅图，一点点花草. .
IGOR: A little paint, a few flowers...
还有两个废弃的枕头. .
couple of throw pillows...
我们那个神秘的小提琴家好像消--
FRANKENSTEIN: It seems our mysterious violinist has disa
消什么？
INGA: Disa what?
消失了
IGOR: Ppeared.
那扇门后有光
FRANKENSTEIN: There's a light coming from behind that door.
跟我来
Follow me.
医生，看
INGA: Doctor, look!
FRANKENSTEIN: Well...
这就可以解释音乐了
this explains the music.
还是暖的
IGOR: It's still warm.
FRANKENSTEIN: Hmmm.
是谁拉过呢？
INGA: Who was playing it?
不管是谁. .
FRANKENSTEIN: Whoever it was...
刚刚吸完雪茄
barely finished putting out his cigar.
这些事太奇怪了
Such strange goings on.
这是什么地方？
What is this place?
音乐房吗？
IGOR: Music room?
这里只有书和材料
INGA: There's nothing here but books and papers!
书和材料
FRANKENSTEIN: Books and papers!
这是我祖父的私人图书室
This is my grandfather's private library!
我感觉得到
I feel it!
看，看这里
Look! Look at this!
[Grunting]
直到，黑暗里. .
FRANKENSTEIN: "Until, from this darkness...
有一道光突然射到我身上
"a sudden light broke in upon me.
一道非常明亮. .
"A light so brilliant and wondrous...
而又简单的光--
"and yet so simple...
把电极从最大变到最小. .
"change the poles from plus to minus...
“从最小变到最大”
"and from minus to plus."
[Panting]
只有我一个人成功的发现了. .
"I alone succeeded in discovering...
生命基因的秘密
"the secret of bestowing life.
更重要的是. .
"Nay, even more...
我自己. .
"I myself...
已经有能力. .
"became capable of bestowing animation...
“让死去的东西再复活！”
"upon lifeless matter!"
成功了
It could work!
腌鱼？
FRANKENSTEIN: Kipper?
谢谢你，医生
INGA: Thank you, Doctor.
有一个微小的细节问题 影响了我的研究速度
"The minuteness of the parts formed a hindrance to my speed.
因此，我下定决心要造出一个. .
"I resolved, therefore, to make the creature
“巨型人.”
"of a gigantic stature."
当然
Of course!
那就会简化一切东西
That would simplify everything.
他的手，脚，器官. .
His veins, feet, hands, organs...
都得比常人的大
would all have to be increased in size.
不错
Exactly.
那他必须有很大的神经组织系统
He would have an enormous schwanstugel.
那还用说
That goes without saying.
Woof!
他会非常受欢迎的
He'll be very popular.
我们的目的是. .
What we're aiming for...
他必须有七英尺高. .
is a being approximately seven feet in height
所有的特征 不论是天生的. .
with all features either congenitally...
还是人造的 都必须保持相当的比例
or artificially proportionate in size.
就像. .
Something like...
这个？
this?
哈罗
FRANKENSTEIN: Hello!
你已经画出来了
You've caught something there.
天然的，是的.简单的，是的 也许还有些怪异
Crude, yes. Primitive, yes. Perhaps even grotesque.
一些说不清的感觉告诉我. .
Yet, something inexplicable tells me...
这个也许就是我们要找的人
that this might be our man.
好了
All right.
这对他来说就已经足够了
That's good enough for the likes of him.
插下去吧
FRANKENSTEIN: Get down.
快些
Now.
真是恶心
FRANKENSTEIN: What a filthy job!
也许会更糟
IGOR: Could be worse.
怎么个糟法？
How?
也许会下雨
Could be raining.
[Footsteps]
快
FRANKENSTEIN: Quick!
需要帮助吗
CONSTABLE: Need a hand?
不用，谢谢了
FRANKENSTEIN: Uh, no, thanks.
我有个助手，谢谢
Have one. Thanks very much.
等等
CONSTABLE: Just a moment!
我认识这里的每个街坊邻居
I know everyone in this neighborhood.
好像从没见过你
I've never seen your face before.
我是弗勒迪.弗朗肯斯丁恩医生. .
I am Dr. Frederick Frankenstein...
刚从美国来
newly arrived from America.
我得知你要来
I was told you were here.
我是亨利 很高兴见到你
I'm Constable Henry. Pleased to meet you.
见到你很高兴
How very nice to meet you.
你的手凉的刺骨
CONSTABLE: You're chilled to the bone!
烤烤火会好些的
A warm fire's just the thing.
有一点御寒的酒就更不错了
A nip from the bottle wouldn't be too bad.
不错
That's the ticket!
如果你还有事的话 我该说声晚安了
If you have everything in hand, I'll say good night.
谢谢你，亨利
Thank you, Constable.
随时听候你的吩咐，先生
At your service, sir, always.
晚安，亨利
Good night, Constable.
晚安
Good night.
真是丑
FRANKENSTEIN: Oh, what an awesome sight.
这真是具有深远意义又虔诚的晚上
What a profound and reverent night is this.
找到这么一具标本. .
With such a specimen for a body...
我们现在唯一需要的 就是一个完美的头脑
all we need now is an equally magnificent brain.
你知道该如何做吗？
You know what to do?
我很清楚
IGOR: I have a pretty good idea.
很好，伙计
FRANKENSTEIN: Good man.
这个怎么到另一边去了？
Wasn't that on the other side?
什么？
IGOR: What?
你的. .
FRANKENSTEIN: Your, uh...
没事
Oh, never mind.
你知道他叫什么吗？
FRANKENSTEIN: Do you have that name?
我知道
IGOR: I have it.
德克
IGOR: H. Delbruck.
汗.德克
FRANKENSTEIN: Hans Delbruck.
[Thunder]
Ahh!
Ahhh!
畸形大脑，请勿使用
他真可怕
INGA: He's hideous!
他很美
FRANKENSTEIN: He's beautiful.
他是我的
And he is mine.
[Thunder]
我们现在是在 跟时间和原理作对
FRANKENSTEIN: We're fighting time and the elements.
你弄好了吗？
Are you ready?
你敢肯定是这样做吗？
IGOR: Are you sure this is how?
不错，书上就是这么写的
Yes! It's all written in the notes!
系好风筝赶紧下来
Tie the kites and hurry down!
为什么要快些下来？
What's the hurry?
也许你会被电死
There's a possibility of electrocution!
你听到了吗？
Do you understand?
我说，你也许会被电死
I say, there's a possibility of electrocution!
你听见了吗？
Do you understand?
我听见了 你叫那么大声做什么？
IGOR: I understand. Why are you shouting?
你已经. .
FRANKENSTEIN: Did you...
你已经系好风筝了吗？
Did you tie the kites?
当然
IGOR: Of course.
FRANKENSTEIN: Oh.
好的，很好
All right. Good.
去检查一下发电机
Check the generator.
是，先生
IGOR: Yes, master.
艾哥尔. .
FRANKENSTEIN: Lgor...
去检查一下主轮上的安全阀
release the safety valve on the main wheel.
是，先生
IGOR: Yes, master.
你能想像汗.德克的脑 在这具身体里吗？
Can you imagine Hans Delbruck's brain in this body?
弗勒迪
INGA: Oh, Frederick.
这一刻就要到了
This is the moment.
亲爱的，你准备好了吗？
Well, dear, are you ready?
是的，医生
Yes, Doctor.
让我升上去
Elevate me.
现在？在这里？
Now? Right here?
是的，把平台升上去
Yes, yes. Raise the platform.
平台
Oh, the platform.
是的，那个
Oh, that! Ja!
自从开天僻地那天. .
From that fateful day...
一把泥土从海中爬起. .
when stinking bits of slime first crawled from the sea
对着冷冷的星空高喊. .
and shouted to the cold stars...
“我是人. . .”
"I am man..."
从那一刻起我们就知道. .
our greatest dread has always been the knowledge
死亡也随之而来
of our own mortality.
但是今晚. .
But tonight...
我们要推翻这种定论. .
we shall have hurled the gauntlet of science
让人们从死亡中解脱出来
into the frightful face of death itself!
今晚. .
Tonight...
我们要升上天堂
we shall ascend into the heavens.
[Thunder]
我们要嘲笑地震
We shall mock the earthquake.
我们要呼风唤雨
We shall command the thunders!
我们要浸入子宫. .
And penetrate into the very womb...
那一块天然的圣地. .
of impervious nature...
入她的核心
herself!
[Thunder]
听我说，开第一道开关
When I say, throw the first switch.
知道了，先生
You've got it, master.
好了. .
Get ready...
准备. .
get set...
开
go!
开第二道开关
Throw the second switch!
开第三道开关
Throw the third switch!
不是第道
Not the third switch.
开，听我的
Throw it, I say!
生命
Life!
生命，你听到我在说话了吗
Life! Do you hear me?
给我的创造物. .
Give my creation...
生命吧
life!
把所有的东西都关上 让我下来
Turn everything off! Bring me down!
什么动静都没有
FRANKENSTEIN: Nothing.
医生，我很抱歉
INGA: Doctor, I'm sorry.
不，不
FRANKENSTEIN: No, no.
高兴点
Be of good cheer.
如果说科学 教会了我们什么的话. .
If science teaches us anything...
那就是接受失败. .
it teaches us to accept our failures...
要像接受成功时一样. .
as well as our successes...
充满风度和尊严
with quiet dignity and grace.
龟孙子，我要掐死你
Son of a bitch bastard, I'll get you for this!
你为什么要这样对我？
What did you do to me?
住手
INGA: Stop it!
你会杀了他的
You'll kill him!
INGA: Ah!
我不想活了
FRANKENSTEIN: I don't want to live!
我不想活了. .
I do not want to live...
非常有风度和尊严
Quiet dignity and grace.
妈妈
FRANKENSTEIN: Ohhh, Mama!
这个人有些不同
ELDER: This man is different.
只要你们跟他稍微说上几句话 就会知道的
You can see that after you've talked to him for five minutes.
是吗？
SECOND ELDER: Yes?
他是一个人形怪物
He's a Frankenstein!
他们都是一样的
They're all alike!
是的
CROWD: Yeah!
这是他们的血统 是遗传，无法改变的
It's in their blood. They can't help it.
所有的科学家都是一样的
All them scientists are alike.
他们说他们是为了我们好
They say they're working for us.
但实际上 他们想的是统治这个世界
What they really want is to rule the world.
[Pounding]
安静
SECOND ELDER: Settle down.
够了
That's enough now!
我可不想让这场会议 变成一场混战
I won't have this meeting become a free-for-all.
你们的这些控诉 是个很严重的问题. .
These are very serious charges you're making
对我们来说更痛苦，你们的长辈. .
and all the more painful to us, your elders
因为我们还处在以前的恶梦中
because we still have nightmares from five times before.
我们还没有听. .
We haven't heard from the man...
这里最有资格发言的人
most qualified to judge the situation fairly.
探长克姆帕
Inspector Kemp.
你可以跟我们讲几句吗
Will you talk to us, please?
暴乱是件很不光彩的事. .
A riot is an ugly thing...
一旦你们有了开始. .
and once you get one started...
就不会有办法. .
there is little chance of stopping it...
阻止流血事件
short of bloodshed.
我认为. .
I think...
在我们要杀一个人之前. .
before we go around killing people...
我们最好要有. .
we had better make damn sure...
确凿的证据
of our evidence.
而且. .
Und...
肯定这个事实. .
we had better confirm the fact...
年轻的弗朗肯斯丁恩. .
that young Frankenstein is indeed...
正在赴他祖父的后程
following in his grandfather's footsteps!
什么
CROWD: What?
赴他祖父的后程，后程
Following in his grandfather's footsteps, footsteps!
CROWD: Oh!
我认为. .
I think...
我该做的事就是. .
what is in order...
去拜访. .
is for me to pay a little visit...
那位医生. .
on the good doctor...
然后和他好好谈谈
and to have a nice, quiet chat.
名誉. .
FRANKENSTEIN: Reputation...
reputation...
医生，你不要这样折磨你自己了吧
INGA: Oh, Doctor, you mustn't do this to yourself.
不要多想
You've got to stop thinking about it.
你甚至都还没动过你的食物
You haven't even touched your food.
好的
FRANKENSTEIN: There!
你动过了，你高兴了吧
I've touched it. Happy?
我永远都不会忘记我的老父亲
I'll never forget my old dad.
每当有什么事情发生时. .
When these things happened to him...
他总爱说
the things he'd say.
说什么？
What did he say?
你在浴室做什么？
"What the hell are you doing in the bathroom?
“给别人一点机会！”
"Give someone else a chance!"
也许这样更好
Maybe it's better this way.
那个可怜的，没生命力的大个子
The poor, lifeless hulk.
也许死了对他来说更好些
Maybe it is better off dead.
MONSTER: Mmmmm!
这是什么？
IGOR: What is this?
斯瓦特
FRANKENSTEIN: Swartzwalter.
MONSTER: Mmmmm!
你喜欢吗？
FRANKENSTEIN: Oh, you like it?
我并不是想把它留给我一人 但它味道确实很好
I'm not partial to deserts myself, but this is excellent.
你在跟谁说话？
IGOR: Who are you talking to?
跟你
FRANKENSTEIN: To you.
你刚才发出了愉快的声音
You just made a yummy sound.
我没有
IGOR: I didn't make a yummy sound.
我听到了
FRANKENSTEIN: I just heard it.
不是我
IGOR: It wasn't me.
INGA: It wasn't me.
如果不是你 不是你. .
FRANKENSTEIN: If it wasn't you and it wasn't you...
MONSTER: Mmmmm!
MONSTER: Mmmmm.
FRANKENSTEIN: Mmmmm.
活了
Alive!
它活了
It's alive!
退后
Stand back.
哈罗
Hello there.
我马上放开你
FRANKENSTEIN: I'll set you free.
MONSTER: Mmmmm.
镇静剂准备好了吗？
Is the sedative ready?
准备好了，医生
INGA: Yes, Doctor.
MONSTER: Mmmmm.
我希望你能. .
FRANKENSTEIN: I want you...
坐起来
to sit up.
Mmmmm.
然后. .
Stand...
站起来
on your feet.
Mmmmm. Mmmmm.
你做得到的
You can do it.
Mmmmm.
现在. .
FRANKENSTEIN: Now...
走路
walk.
医生，我害怕
INGA: Doctor, I'm frightened.
甭担心
FRANKENSTEIN: Don't worry.
好的
Good.
Good!
MONSTER: Agggh!
怎么了？出什么事了？
FRANKENSTEIN: What is it? What's the matter?
快点，给他--
Quick, give him the...
给他什么？
IGOR: Give him the what?
三个音节
Three syllables.
第一个
First syllable.
听起来像. .
Sounds like...
head！听起来像head
INGA: Head! Sounds like head.
Bed...
Uh, sed...
-是Sed！ -是Sed！
- Sed!   - Sed!
是Sed. .
Sed...
第二个音节
Second syllable.
一个字. .
Little word. This, that, the...
IGOR: A...
INGA: Oh!
IGOR: Sed-a...
INGA: Sed-a...
下流字！ 他说了一个下流字！
IGOR: Dirty word! He said a dirty word!
听起来像. .
BOTH: Sounds like...
INGA: Uh... give!
IGOR: Sed-a-give!
给他一个sed-a-giVe！
Give him a sed-a-give!
他说的是“镇静剂”
INGA: Tive! Sedative!
在鼻子上
IGOR: On the nosey!
MONSTER: Agggh!
Agggh!
镇-静-剂？
FRANKENSTEIN: Sed-a-give?
弗勒迪，你没事吧？
INGA: Frederick, are you all right?
没事
FRANKENSTEIN: Yes.
对不起，亲爱的？
Would you excuse me, dear?
没关系，医生
INGA: Oh, of course, Doctor.
艾哥尔
FRANKENSTEIN: Lgor.
我可以跟你谈谈吗？
May I speak to you?
当然
IGOR: Of course.
坐下
Sit down.
谢谢你
Thank you.
不，坐在上面
No, up here.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你给我的那个脑. .
Now, that brain that you gave me...
是汗.德克的吗？
was it Hans Delbruck's?
不是
- No. - Ah!
很好
Good.
你可以告诉我. .
Uh... would you mind telling me...
我放进去的. .
whose brain...
是谁的脑吗？
I did put in?
你不会生气吧？
You won't be angry?
我不会的
I will not be angry.
一个叫布的人
Abby someone.
布的人
布什么？
Abby who?
布.真常
Abby Normal.
大概就是这个名字
I'm almost sure that was the name.
你的意思就是说 你给了我一个不正常的脑. .
Are you saying that I put an abnormal brain
让我放进了这个七英尺半高. .
into a seven and a half foot long
五十四英尺宽. .
fifty-four inch wide...
的大猩猩身上？
gorilla?
这就是你要说的吗？
Is that what you're telling me?
快点，给他--
IGOR: Quick, give him the...
什么？
INGA: What?
三个音节？是的--
Three syllables? Yes...
[Pounding on door]
会是谁？
FRANKENSTEIN: Who could that be?
英佳，快去开门！
FRANKENSTEIN: Inga, quick!
看看是谁
See who that is.
你. .
You...
把那个东西. .
put that thing...
放回到手术桌上去. .
back on the operating table...
把他捆得紧紧的
and strap him down tightly!
-你要去哪？ -去梳洗一下
- Where are you going? - To wash up.
我看来必须正常点 我们看起来都要正常些
I've got to look normal. All of us must behave normally.
怪物
FRANKENSTEIN: Ha! Monsters!
射得好
KEMP: Excellent shot.
这是二十世纪
FRANKENSTEIN: This is the 20th century.
怪物已经过时了 就像小丑一样
Monsters are passe, like goblins.
对这个镇上的好人就不是的了. .
KEMP: Not to the good people of this village...
医生
Herr Doktor.
对他们来说 这是件摆在眼前的事
To them, he is a very real thing.
特别是当有个人形怪物. .
Especially when there is a Frankenstein...
住在这所房子时
residing in this house.
[Thunk-thunk thunk-thunk-thunk]
很漂亮的手法
Nice grouping.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我想大概再也没有 比你更聪明的人了吧. .
I wouldn't think an intelligent fellow like you...
居然会相信这种迷信说法
would fall for this superstitious rot.
我相信的并不是迷信. .
It is not superstition that worries me...
而是基因和. . .染色体！
but genes and... chromosomes!
废话
Rubbish!
是么，但这里是. . .特兰西瓦尼亚
You might say, but this is... Transylvania!
而你是一个. . .人形怪物
and you are a... Frankenstein!
你. .
You, uh...
好像对这种话题有些心神不宁
seem unusually upset by this discussion.
没那回事
Not in the least.
CAT: Meoww!
我觉得很有趣
I find it amusing.
[Crash]
过去是很有趣
Well, this was fun.
如果你不介意的话 我想休息了
If you don't mind, I'm tired.
那么我就要向村民传达你的话. .
Then I may give the villagers your complete assurance
你对那个
that you have no interest whatsoever
你祖父的学术完全不感兴趣？
in carrying on your grandfather's work?
MONSTER: Mmmmm!
我可以把这当成是同意吗？
KEMP: May I take that for a yes?
FRANKENSTEIN: Mmmmm.
很好
KEMP: Very well.
你找得到出去的路吗？
FRANKENSTEIN: Can you find your way out?
当然
KEMP: Of course.
等我们再次见面时. .
Until we meet again...
男爵
uh, Baron.
随便您什么时候来
Drop by any time.
我们随时恭候
We're always open.
[Muttering]
维克托
BLUCHER: Oh, Victor.
Victor!
我们成功了
We have done it!
我马上就放开你
BLUCHER: I'm going to set you free.
你喜欢这样吗，亲爱的？
Would you like that, eine schatze kopf?
MONSTER: Mmmmm.
他们想伤害你
They wanted to hurt you.
但是我会帮你的
But I'm going to help you.
谢天谢地这一切总算是结束了
FRANKENSTEIN: Thank heavens that's over with.
布鲁切
Frau Blucher!
[Horses whinny]
停下
BLUCHER: Stop!
不要靠近
Don't come closer!
你在做什么？
FRANKENSTEIN: What are you doing?
我要放了他
I'm setting him free!
不行，不行，你不能这样干
INGA: No! No, you mustn't!
我就要这么干
BLUCHER: Yes!
你有毛病吗？
FRANKENSTEIN: Are you insane?
他会杀了你的
He'll kill you!
不，他不会的
BLUCHER: No, he won't.
他就跟一只羊羔一样温顺
He is as gentle as a lamb.
后退，看在上帝的份上
FRANKENSTEIN: Stand back, for the love of God!
他的脑有问题
He has a rotten brain!
不，他的脑很好
BLUCHER: It's a good brain!
不，是坏的，是坏的
FRANKENSTEIN: It's rotten! Rotten!
IGOR: Lx-nay on the otten-ray.
我不怕
I am not afraid.
我知道他喜欢什么
I know what he likes.
Agggh!
那音乐
FRANKENSTEIN: That music!
是的，它在你的血液里
BLUCHER: Yes, it's in your blood.
在所有人形怪物的血液里
It's in the blood of all Frankensteins.
当语言没用时 它就能进入它们的灵魂里
It reaches the soul when words are useless.
你的祖父就经常对它们拉提琴
Your grandfather used to play it to his creature.
是你
FRANKENSTEIN: It was you!
不错
Yes!
-那天晚上是你在拉提琴 -是的
- You played music that night! - Yes!
把我们引到这里来
To get us here!
不错
Yes!
是你吸的雪茄
That was your smoldering cigar!
不错
Yes!
是你把我祖父的书留给我的！
You left my grandfather's book out for me!
是的
Yes!
-那样的话，我就能-- -没错
- So that I would... - Yes!
你和维克托是. .
You and Victor were...
是的，是的，不错
Yes! Yes! Say it!
他是我的男朋友
He was my boyfriend!
MONSTER: Owwww!
Owwww1
Agggh! Agggh!
你永远都抓不到他了
BLUCHER: You'll never catch him now!
他自由了
He's free!
你听到了吗？
Do you hear?
自由了
Free!
Agggh!
跑了
FRANKENSTEIN: Gone.
Gone!
我们必须找到他
We've got to find him!
在他还没杀人之前找到他
We've got to find him before he kills someone.
我做了什么啊？
What have I done?
上帝. .
Oh, God in heaven...
我做了什么啊？
what have I done?
我爱. .
[Singing] Oh, I love...
爱我可爱的花朵
my pretty little flower.
我爱. .
Oh, I love...
爱我可爱的花朵
my pretty little flower.
我爱我的花
Oh, I love my flower.
MONSTER: Mmmmm.
那个怪物跑了
That monster is loose.
必须把木板订牢点
Boards must be tight.
好了
There.
谢天谢地你已经让海尔格睡了
Thank God you put Helga to bed.
我也没有办法 对付这种怪物只能如此
With all this monster business, I take no chances
但是爸爸，我并没让她去睡
MAMA: But, Papa, I told you I was turning the rostbraten.
我跟你说让你把海尔格--
I asked you to put Helga to...
现在给它一个吻说声再见
HELGA: Now throw a kiss and say bye-bye.
MONSTER: Mmm-mmm.
亲爱的，什么都没有了
Oh, dear. Nothing left.
我们现在还可以丢什么呢？
What shall we throw in now?
也许她在浴室里
PAPA: Maybe she was in the bathroom.
我还没上楼看
MAMA: I didn't look upstairs.
我以为你去过了
I thought you did.
你还没看过楼上？
You didn't look upstairs?
坐下
HELGA: Sit down.
Sit down!
BOTH: Ahhh!
[Peaceful music playing]
我只乞求来一个访客. .
A visitor's all I ask...
来陪我一会儿
a temporary companion to help pass a few hours.
Agggh!
谢谢你，主
Thank you, Lord!
谢谢你
Thank you!
MONSTER: Mmmmm.
不，不，不要说话
BLINDMAN: No, no. Don't speak.
不要说话
Don't say a word.
这是上帝给我的礼物和惊喜
My joy and my prize from heaven.
你一定是你们那里最高的人
You must've been the tallest in your class.
我叫哈罗德，我一个人过活
My name's Harold. I live alone.
你叫什么
- What's your name? - Mmmmm.
什么？
What?
没名字
- Mmmmm. - Mmmmm. Nope.
对不起
Forgive me.
我没想到你是个哑巴
I didn't realize you were mute.
你看上帝想的多周到
You see how heaven plans?
我，一个穷瞎子. 你，一具哑巴
Me, a poor blind man, and you, a mute.
一个好大的哑巴
An incredibly big mute.
我的孩子，你的手好冰冷
Your hand is frozen, my child.
喝点汤如何？
How does soup sound?
Mmmmm.
我知道对于一个又饥又渴的人. .
I know what it means to be cold and hungry...
能从一个善心人 那得到帮助有多么的重要
to have some kindness from a stranger.
准备好了吗？
Ready for soup?
Mmmmm.
拿着你的碗
Hold out your bowl, then.
我的朋友, 你不知道你的来访对我有多么重要. .
My friend, you don't know what your visit means to me
我一直盼望着有个人来看我
how long I've waited for another human being.
Owwww!
我们会忘记这些微小的快乐--
We tend to forget the simple pleasures...
Owwww!
这是幸福最基本的原则
The basis for true happiness.
是的，是的. .
Yes, yes, yes. Oh...
要点酒吗？
A little wine with your soup?
Mmmmm.
好的，好的
Good. Good.
Mmmmm.
Mmmmm. Mmmmm.
BLINDMAN: Uh-huh.
MONSTER:
Mm-mmm, mm-mmm, mm-mmm.
好的，好的，是的，先生
Good. Good. Yes, sir.
等等
Wait!
我们先干一杯. .
A toast. A toast to...
是的，希望我们友谊长存
Yes! To long friendship.
你一定很饿了
How hungry you must have been.
现在给你一个小小的惊喜
Now for a little surprise.
我一直都留着, 想在一具特殊的场合拿出来. .
For a special occasion, I've been saving...
雪茄
cigars.
MONSTER: Mmmmm?
拿一根
BLINDMAN: Take one.
Mmmmm!
什么？
What?
不要紧，火是好东西
No, no. Fire is good.
Mmmmm!
火是好东西，是的
Fire is good... yes.
火是我们的朋友
Fire is our friend.
我示范给你看看
I'll show you.
Mmmmm mmmmm.
Mmmmm...
明白了吗？明白了吗？
You see? You see?
你拿着你的雪茄了吗？
Do you have your cigar?
让我帮你
Let me see.
好的
All right.
现在，现在
Now... now... now.
把它放在这
Just hold it right there.
等头上点烧后再吸
Don't inhale until the tip glows.
Owwww!
Mmmmm!
Agggh!
等等
Wait!
你要去哪？
Where are you going?
我还要去煮点浓咖啡
I was going to make espresso.
Agggh!
[Violin playing]
好了
Now!
Agggh!
快点，把镇静剂拿来
FRANKENSTEIN: Hurry! Bring the sedative!
MONSTER: Agggh! Agggh!
Agggh!
Owwww!
Agggh...
Aggghmmmm...
我们抓住它了
FRANKENSTEIN: He's out!
我知道
IGOR: I know.
我要进去了
FRANKENSTEIN: I'm going in.
把蜡烛给我
Bring me that candle.
-不！ -给他
- No! - Yes!
爱是唯一一样. .
Love is the only thing...
可以救这个生物的东西了
that can save this poor creature.
我会让他相信他是被爱的. .
And I will convince him that he is loved
即使花掉我的生命也在所不惜
even at the cost of my own life.
不管你们听到什么声音. .
No matter what you hear...
不管我多么哀苦地请求你们. .
no matter how cruelly I beg you...
不管我叫的有多么恐怖. .
no matter how terribly I may scream...
都不要把门打开. .
do not open this door...
否则你们会让我 所做的一切努力都白费
or you will undo everything I've worked for.
不要打开门
Do not open this door!
好的，医生
INGA: Yes, Doctor.
祝你好运
IGOR: Nice working with you.
MONSTER: Mmmmm...
Agggh!
Mmmmm.
让我出去
Get me the hell out of here.
你们是怎么回事？ 我刚刚只是开开玩笑
What's wrong with you? I was joking!
你们难道听不出来吗 我只是开开玩笑？
Don't you know a joke when you hear one?
老天，放我出去
FRANKENSTEIN: Jesus Christ, get me out of here!
开门！ 不然，我让你们好看
Open this door! I'll kick your rotten heads in!
妈妈
Mommy!
不行
BLUCHER: Nein!
Agggh!
[Mutters]
你好，帅哥
Hello, handsome!
你真是个帅小伙
You're a good-looking fellow.
人们笑你，人们讨厌你
People laugh at you. People hate you.
他们为什么讨厌你？
Why do they hate you?
是因为他们妒忌
Because they are jealous!
MONSTER: Mmmmm.
看看你那孩子般的脸. .
Look at that boyish face...
那甜密的微笑
that sweet smile.
你想谈谈体力吗？
You want to talk about physical strength?
你想谈谈结实的肌肉吗？
You want to talk about sheer muscle?
你想谈谈参加奥运会的梦想吗？
You want to talk about the Olympian ideal?
你是神
You are a God!
听我说
Listen to me.
你并不恶魔
You are not evil.
你是个神
You are good!
是个漂亮的孩子
This is a nice boy.
是个乖孩子
This is a good boy.
你妈妈的天使
This is a mother's angel.
我要让整个世界知道. .
And I want the world to know...
不会有任何羞耻的告诉他们. .
once and for all and without any shame...
我们爱他
that we love him!
Oh...
我要教你如何走路. .
I'm going to teach you how to walk...
如何说话，如何移动 如何思考
how to speak, how to move, how to think.
我们一起. .
Together...
你和我，我们要作出. .
you and I, are going to make...
自从火的创造以来. .
the greatest single contribution to science...
对科学巨大的贡献
since the creation of fire!
弗兰肯斯坦恩医生，你没事吧？
INGA: Dr. Fronkensteen, are you all right?
我的名字叫. .
My name...
弗朗肯斯丁恩
is Frankenstein!
各位尊贵的来宾 女士们，先生们. .
Distinguished colleagues, ladies and gentlemen
今天我很荣幸在这里向你们介绍. .
it is my great privilege of introducing to you
一个出名而又声名狼籍. .
a man whose family name was once both famous
的人
and infamous.
现在我将介绍. .
And now, may I present...
男爵弗勒迪.弗朗肯斯丁恩医生
Dr. Baron Frederick von Frankenstein.
我的同--
My fellow scien...
PERSON: Sssssssss!
--僚们
FRANKENSTEIN: Tists...
神经外科医生们. .
and neurosurgeons...
女士们，先生们
ladies and gentlemen.
几个星期前 我们讨论了些. .
A few short weeks ago, coming from a background
根深蒂固的传统科学. .
traditionally grounded in scientific fact
对此，我着手进行了一项实验--
I began an experiment in...
听起来很不可信--
incredulous as it may sound...
让死去的东西再复活
the reanimation of dead tissue.
我现在要展示给你们看的. .
What I have to offer you might possibly be
大概是条通向不朽之路的东西
the gateway to immortality.
现在我将介绍. .
Ladies and gentlemen, may I present
你们智力和哲学上的乐趣. .
for your intellectual and philosophical pleasure
我的创造物
the creature!
各位，请不要惊慌
Please!
坐回你们的位子
Remain in your seats.
我们不是小孩子
We are not children.
我们是科学家
We are scientists.
我会让你们看到 没什么好怕的
I assure you there's nothing to fear.
首先，我要向你们展示的是. .
First, may I offer for your consideration
神经科上. .
a neurological demonstration...
小脑最基本的作用--
of the primary cerebellar functions...
保持平衡. .
balance...
与协调
and coordination.
用脚根先着地走路
Walk heel-to-toe.
后退
Backwards!
你们已经看到他的表演了. .
You've seen the creature perform...
这是很简单的机械运动
simple mechanics of motor activity.
接下来你们将看到的是. .
For what you're about to see...
天赋的领域
we must enter into the realm of genius.
女士们，先生们. .
Ladies and gentlemen...
诸位太太，诸位先生. .
mesdames and messieurs...
小姐们，小伙子们
damen and herren...
对于这个曾经口龄不清. .
from what was an inarticulate mass...
也没有生命活力的机体组织. .
of lifeless tissues...
我现在想要让大家 看到的是一个有修养的. .
may I now present a cultured...
老练的. .
sophisticated...
镇上的人
man about town.
开始
Hit it!
[Singing] If you're blue...
and you don't know where to go to...
why don't you go where fashion sits?
Mmmmin' mm mmm ritz.
[Singing] Different types who wear a day coat...
pants with stripes or cutaway coat...
perfect fits.
Mmmmin' mm mmm ritz.
[Singing] Dressed up like a million dollar trouper
Tryin' mighty hard to look like Gary Cooper
Ooper dooper.
[Singing] Come let's mix where Rockefellers
walk with sticks or umbrellers...
in their mitts.
Mmmmin' mm mmm ritz.
MONSTER: Agggh!
没事
FRANKENSTEIN: It's nothing.
5，6，7，8
Five, six, seven, eight.
你想让我在这里丢丑吗？
You want me to look foolish?
各位，各位，请安静下来
Please, I beg you!
请不要这样，不要侮辱他
For safety's sake, don't humiliate him!
回来
Come back!
我不会让你破坏我的工作
I won't let you destroy my work.
我命令你回来
I command you to come back.
Agggh!
像个被锁在笼子里的野兽
FRANKENSTEIN: Chained like a beast in a cage.
医生，这真是太可怕了
INGA: Oh, Doctor, I feel so terrible.
只有一个答案
FRANKENSTEIN: There's only one answer.
只要我能平衡. .
If I could equalize the imbalance
他的脑脊髓液. .
in his cerebral spinal fluid...
他就会很正常了
he'd be as right as rain.
但要怎样做了？
But how?
怎样做？在还来得及时
How? Before it's too late.
噢，弗勒迪. .
INGA: Oh, Frederick...
如果有办法让我帮你. .
if only there was some way I could...
FRANKENSTEIN: Mmm.
. . .减轻这种痛苦
INGA: Relieve your torture.
FRANKENSTEIN: Mmm. Mmm. Mmm.
我希望我可以. .
INGA: I wish there was some way I could...
FRANKENSTEIN: Mmm. Mmm. Mmm.
. . .让你不要这么难受
INGA: Relieve the tension.
但愿我能让你安静下来
If I could give you a little peace.
医生，我有. .
Doctor, I have...
医生？
Doctor?
什么事？
FRANKENSTEIN: What is it?
医生？你在哪？
Doctor? Where are you?
你走时，我收到了这份电报
BLUCHER: Doctor, this cable came while you were gone.
我想我告诉过你. .
FRANKENSTEIN: I thought I told you...
在我工作时不要打扰我
never to interrupt me while I'm working!
对不起，医生
BLUCHER: I'm sorry, Doctor.
我认为这很紧急
I thought this was an emergency.
你的未婚妻要来了
Your fiancee will be arriving any second.
什么？伊丽莎白？今晚要来？
FRANKENSTEIN: What? Elizabeth? Here tonight?
是的 我马上就去为她准备房间
BLUCHER: Yes. I will go prepare her room at once.
我建议你最好马上穿戴好
I suggest you put on a tie.
亲爱的
Darling!
FRANKENSTEIN: Darling!
-惊喜吗？ -惊喜
- Surprised? - Surprised.
-爱我吗？ -爱你
- Love me? - Love you.
FRANKENSTEIN: Well...
好了，我们进去吧
Let's turn in.
亲爱的
ELIZABETH: Darling!
你一定很累了
FRANKENSTEIN: I'm sure you're tired.
我来付费
I'll pay the driver.
亲爱的
IGOR: Darling!
什么？
ELIZABETH: What?
-惊喜吗？ -我. . .是的
- Surprised? - I, uh... yes.
-爱我吗？
- Love me? - Well...
好了，我们进去吧
IGOR: Well, let's turn in.
亲爱的
FRANKENSTEIN: Darling!
什么都不要说 只是一段临时表演
IGOR: Say nothing. Act casual.
准备好了吗？
FRANKENSTEIN: Ready?
我想
ELIZABETH: I think.
是的
Yes.
我真的是有些累了
I am a bit tired after all.
我的助手 英佳和艾哥尔
FRANKENSTEIN: My assistants, Inga and lgor.
你好？
ELIZABETH: How do you do?
How do you do?
这是我的未婚妻，伊丽莎白
FRANKENSTEIN: This is my financier Elizabeth.
很高兴见到你
INGA: I'm happy to meet you.
未婚妻
FRANKENSTEIN: Financee.
请问，亲爱的
ELIZABETH: Excuse me, darling.
你具体都做些什么呢？
What is it exactly that you do do?
INGA: Uh...
我是在实验室里帮他做些事
I assist Dr. Frankenstein in the laboratory.
我们对一些事进行讨论
We have intellectual discussions.
我们之前正在谈论一个问题
We were having one as you were driving up.
FRANKENSTEIN: Nein!
艾哥尔，帮我们把行李提上来
Lgor, help me with the bags.
好的
IGOR: Soitainly.
你带着那个金发的 我来扶这位
You take the blonde. I'll take the one in the toiban.
Ggggrrrrr!
不要胡闹了
FRANKENSTEIN: Stop that.
拿行李
The luggage.
是，先生
IGOR: Yes, master.
女士，请这边走
FRANKENSTEIN: Ladies, this way.
如果女人的事上你需要帮助的话--
IGOR: If you need help with the girls...
Agggh!
JAILOR: Ha ha ha!
你现在平静下来了
You settle down now.
我们就会成为同伴的
'Cause we're gonna be pals.
对吧？
Right?
MONSTER: Agggh!
很好
JAILOR: Nice and cozy.
就错老朋友似的
Just like old friends.
MONSTER: Mmmmm.
Mmmmm.
怎么了？
JAILOR: What's the matter?
你怕火？
You're afraid of this fire?
这不会伤害你的
This can't hurt you.
明白吗
- See? - Mmmmm!
你这个怪物
Some monster you are.
妈妈说得对
Mama was right.
小孩子是不许玩火的
Little boys ain't supposed to play with fire.
MONSTER: Mmmmm!
是吗？ 因为他们也许会受到伤害
Is they? 'Cause they might get hurt!
MONSTER: Agggh!
安静
KEMP: Silence!
举起来
Up.
暴乱是件不光彩的事
A riot is an ugly thing.
但现在是我们该这样做的时候了
I think it is just about time we had one!
是的
CROWD: Yeah!
杀了那个怪物
Kill the monster!
他会因为制造出一个怪物. .
He will curse the day...
而受到诅咒的
[Garbled] That he was born a Frankenstein!
什么？
CROWD: What?
他会因为制造出一个怪物 而受到诅咒的
KEMP: He will curse the day that he was born a Frankenstein.
是的
CROWD: Yeah!
跑了
FRANKENSTEIN: Loose!
他跑了
He's broken loose!
你知道这意味着什么吗？
Do you know what that means?
亲爱的，你不用担心
ELIZABETH: Darling, you mustn't worry so.
我想你是对的
FRANKENSTEIN: I suppose you're right.
我当然是对的
Of course I am.
好了，不要多想了
Now come along.
如果没有你我该怎么办？
What would I do without you?
如果我受到惊吓的话 就可以到你的房间去吧？
Is your room down the hall if I get the frights?
是的，但是今晚，在这种情况下. .
Yes. But I thought tonight, under the circumstances...
我该在这儿陪着你
I might stay here with you.
你现在就想要我吗 就在我们快要结婚时. .
Would you want me now, so soon before our wedding...
就在我们隔的如此近时？
so near we could almost touch it?
是的
FRANKENSTEIN: Yes!
好孩子
ELIZABETH: Whoa, boy!
或者. .
Or...
你该再等等. .
to wait just a little while longer...
等到当我能毫无疑虑把自己给你时. .
when I can give myself without hesitation
当我完全地. .
when I can be totally, unashamedly...
合法地是你的时，好吗？
and legally yours?
这是个很难的选择
That's a tough choice.
你是个很难缠的男人
You're a tough guy.
[Smack]
我想你是对的
I suppose you're right.
当然了，我总是对的
Of course I am. I always am.
跟我吻别吧
Kiss me and say good night.
不要用舌头
No tongues.
晚安，亲爱的
Good night, darling.
晚安，甜心
Good night, sweetheart.
-我爱你 -我也爱你
- I love you. - I love you, too.
你爱我吗
- You love me? - Mm-hmm.
我爱你，宝贝
- I love you, honey. - Ha ha ha.
做个好梦，亲爱的
Sweet dreams, darling.
再见，不要被臭虫咬了
Good night. Don't let the bedbugs bite.
MONSTER: Mmmmm...
Agggh!
[Singing] He has loosed
the fateful lightning...
of his terrible swift sword.
His truth is marching on.
Da-aaa da da da da da.
Glory, glory, hallelujah.
Glory, glory, hallelujah...
ELIZABETH: Aaaahhhhh!
[Dogs barking]
MONSTER: Mmmmm...
我在哪？
Where am I?
Aahhh!
你是谁？你是什么？
Who are you? What are you?
你想要什么？
What do you want?
Mmmmm.
不要冲动
Calm down.
我不怕你
I'm not afraid of you.
你想要多少钱？ 我的父亲非常有钱
How much do you want? My father's very rich.
你可以拥有整个世界
You would have the entire world.
你必须在11：30之前送我回去
I must be back by 11:30.
我很慎重的警告你
I'm expecting a very important call.
MONSTER: Mmmmm...
说话！你为什么不说话？
Speak! Why don't you speak?
你想做什么？
What are you doing?
你是开玩笑的吧
Oh, you can't be serious.
Mmmmm...
我. .
I'm...
我的天
Oh, my God. Woof!
Aaarrr...
Uuuuhhhh...
我已经订婚了
I'm engaged.
而且，而且. .
And, and...
我从没. .
It was never...
Ah! Ooh! Ah!
Aah!
[Singing] Oh...
生命的甜蜜. .
sweet mystery of life...
我总算发现了你
at last I've found you!
- [Grunting] - [Singing] Oh!
我总算知道了. .
At last I know...
你武器的秘密
the secret of your arms!
Sshhh!
告诉我你是怎么想的
Penny for your thoughts.
Mmmmm!
你真是无药可救了
You're incorrigible!
是吗？
Aren't you?
你的拉练
You little zipper neck.
Mmmmm!
很好，七是我的幸运数字
All right. Seven has always been my lucky number.
过来，你这个可爱的怪物
Come here, you hot monster!
[Violin playing]
这是什么？
What is it?
出什么事了？
What's the matter?
是那音乐吗？
Is it that music?
大概是从村庄那边传来的
It's probably from some nearby cottage.
没什么好担心的
Nothing to worry about.
你要去哪？
Where are you going?
你们男人都这样
You men are all alike.
变得比说得还快. .
Seven or eight quick ones, and you're off with the boys...
你们这些吹牛精
to boast and brag.
最好把你的嘴闭起来
You better keep your mouth shut!
我想我爱上他了
Oh, I think I love him.
[Violin playing]
看，他回来了
INGA: Oh, look! He's coming back!
看
Oh, look!
继续拉！是音乐带他回来的
Keep playing! It's the music that's bringing him back!
上来啊
Come on.
上来，加油
Come on. Come on.
你可以做到的
You can do it!
加油！你可以做到的
Come on! You can do it!
MONSTER: Agggh!
不要碰他
FRANKENSTEIN: Don't touch him!
让他自己上来
He wants to do it himself!
你做得到的
You can do it!
自己上来，我的创造物
Please! My creation!
MONSTER: Agggggh!
快，扶住他
FRANKENSTEIN: Quick! Catch him!
作好交换的准备了吗？
Have the preparations been made for the transference?
是的
INGA: Yes.
你真的要这样做？
IGOR: You sure you want to go through with this?
这是唯一可以救他的办法
FRANKENSTEIN: It's the only thing that can save him.
你知不知道这是在拿你们俩的生命冒险？
IGOR: You realize you're risking both your lives?
[Sour note]
我知道
FRANKENSTEIN: Yes.
我去打开开关
IGOR: I'll switch it off!
我怎么知道什么时候关电源？
INGA: How will I know when they are done?
医生说15分钟
IGOR: The doctor said to allow 15 minutes...
一分不能多，一分不能少
not one second more or less.
还有多久？
INGA: How long now?
还差两分钟
IGOR: Two more minutes.
1，2，3
KEMP: Ein, zwei, drei!
Ein, zwei, drei!
1，2，3
是什么声音？
INGA: What's that noise?
不知道
IGOR: I don't know.
还剩多久？
INGA: What's the time?
快到了
IGOR: Almost time.
是村民们
INGA: It's the villagers!
不，不
INGA: No! No!
请不要
Please!
只剩下七秒了
Just another seven seconds!
不，不
INGA: No! No!
不，不，不
INGA: No! No! No!
把他放下
MONSTER: Put that man down!
是那个怪物
VILLAGER: It's the monster!
SECOND VILLAGER: Nah!
我说把那个人放下
I said put that man down!
你以为你是谁 对这些人下命令？
KEMP: and who are you that you order these people about?
我是那个怪物
MONSTER: I am the monster!
我们知道你是怪物
KEMP: I see that you are the monster.
从我开始记事以来. .
As long as I can remember...
我就知道人们讨厌我
people have hated me.
他们总会被我的模样. .
They looked at my face and body...
吓跑
and ran away in horror.
我就决定既然我不能激起人们的爱. .
I decided if I could not inspire love...
虽然那是我最大的愿望. .
which was my deepest hope...
我就要让他们恐惧！
I would instead cause fear!
我活下来了. .
I live...
是因为这个疯子天才. .
because this poor half-crazed genius...
他给了我生命
has given me life.
他让我觉得自己是美丽的
He alone held an image of me as something beautiful.
为了让事情. .
Then, when it would have been easy...
更简单些. .
to stay out of danger...
他用自己的身体作实验. .
he used his body as a guinea pig...
给了我一个健康的大脑. .
to give me a calmer brain...
让我能正常的. .
and a somewhat more sophisticated way...
表达自己想说的话
of expressing myself.
当然这种情况 是完全不同的
KEMP: This is, of course, an entirely different situation.
作为这个村的首领. .
As leader of this community...
我可以第一个向你传达我的友好吗
may I be the first to offer you my hand in friendship.
谢谢你
MONSTER: Thank you.
我们都欢迎你
KEMP: You are entirely welcome.
好了，现在都上我家去吃些松糕 喝点葡萄酒吧
Now let us go to my house for some sponge cake and wine.
[Pop]
糟糕
Oh, shit!
去木场
To the lumberyard!
[Frankenstein singing] Da dum da-dum.
Dee dum da-dum.
Dee dum da da dum...
哈罗. .
Hello...
弗朗肯斯丁恩太太
Mrs. Frankenstein.
INGA: Mrs. Frankenstein.
多美的名字啊
What a beautiful name!
亲爱的
Oh, darling.
你的帽子
Hold on to your hat.
什么？
What?
我一会就回来
I'll be right back.
W-w-w-wow!
W-w-w-w-wow!
Oh, ho, ho!
[Singing] Dee dum da-dum.
Dee dum da-da...
我在这等你
I'm holding on to it, darling.
一会就好
INGA: Just a few more seconds!
[Humming "The Wedding March"]
[Lnga singing] La dee da dum...
La dee da da...
La la la da...
La dum...
La dee da dum...
Da dee da da...
La dee da da...
La la...
[Elizabeth humming "Battle Hymn of the Republic"]
亲爱的 我希望爸爸的晚会没让我厌烦
ELIZABETH: Honey, I hope Daddy's party didn't bore you.
他是为你开的
He did it just for you.
说吧，你喜欢它
Say you liked it.
MONSTER: Mm-hmm.
宝贝，你看到了吗？
ELIZABETH: Honey, did you see?
这个是给你放衬衣的箱子
Here's a hamper just for your shirts.
另一具是放袜子和内衣的
The other one is just for socks and poo-poo undies.
我来了
Here I come.
Hhhhh!
[Snorts]
[Singing] Tchi-tchi tchi-tchi-tchi.
Tchi-tchi-tchi tchi tchi tchi.
Doo doo-doo doo-doo doo doo.
Da-da da da da-da da.
Tsssssst!
Mmmmmmmm...
FRANKENSTEIN: Mmmmm...
Mmmmm!
INGA: Mmmmm!
这种感觉是相互呼应的
The feeling is mutual.
真是太奇妙了
It's a puzzlement.
我一直都想问的是. .
There's something I've always wanted to ask...
那一次手术
about that operation.
在那次交换手术中. .
In the transference part...
那个怪物得到了你一半聪明的脑
the monster got part of your wonderful brain.
你从他那里得到了什么呢？
What did you get from him?
Mmmmmmmmmmmmmmmm!!
INGA: No! Oh!
我真不敢相信
I don't believe... Oh!
Ow! Oh, oh!
[Singing] Oh...
生命的神秘. .
sweet mystery of life...
我总算发现了你
at last I've found you!